Guide to the Richard Courant Papers MC 150
New York University Archives
- Series I: Files from the Home of Ernst Courant, 1907-1969
  - Subseries A: Correspondence
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with relatives such as “Gerta,” “Rose,” “Dolly,” and “Ursula,” as well as correspondence with Heinrich Düker, G. Waldo Dunnington, and Albert Einstein
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with William Feller
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence with Werner Fenchel, Gustav Fischer Publishers, Donald Flanders, and Abraham Flexner
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence with William Flexner, Wilhelm Flügge, and Abraham Fraenkel
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence with Hermann Fränkel and K.O. Friedrichs
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with the American consul in Hamburg re: immigration visa for Ilse Benfey and communication with German Consulate General in New York
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence with Georges Giraud, Henry Goldman (of Goldman Sachs), Sydney Goldstein, Maria Goeppert-Meyer
    - Correspondence: C-G, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Includes corresondence with Emil Julius Gumbel and Albert Einstein
    - Correspondence: Courant Family, 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with Nina Courant, Courant's children, and other family members
    - Correspondence: Courant, Fritz, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Courant, Fritz, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Courant, Fritz, 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Courant, Fritz, 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Courant, Fritz - Illness, 1939-1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Includes correspondence with doctors in America and Brazil re: Fritz Courant's illness and death
    - Correspondence: D, 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Includes correspondence with Gustav Doetsch and Jesse Douglas
    - Correspondence: Deutsch, Monroe (Berkeley), 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Monroe Deutsch, Vice President of Berkeley, re: possible appointment there for Courant in 1934
    - Correspondence: Divorce, 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Materials relating to Courant’s divorce from his first wife, Nelly Neumann in 1916. Includes a 1930s copy of Courant’s official divorce certificate from 1916, as well as correspondence with Nelly Neumann and Max Neumann, Nelly's father.
    - Correspondence: E, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with Dmitri Egorov re: Moscow Mathematical Society, Paul Ehrenfest, Theodor Estermann, and Arnold Eucken
    - Correspondence: F to L, 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with Abraham Flexner, Abraham Fraenkel, Felix Frankfurter, Kurt Friedrichs, Jakob Goldschmidt, Kurt Grelling, Gustav Hertz and Fritz John. This folder includes a list of professors dismissed from Göttingen in 1933.
    - Correspondence: F to L, 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Correspondence to/from Theodor von Karman, Max von Laue, Solomon Lefschetz, Hans Lewy, Tullio Levi-Civita, and Rudolf Lüneburg.
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence with Gaston Julia and Max Born (in his official position as dean of the mathematics and physics faculty at Göttingen)
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence with William Feller and Werner Fenchel
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with Abraham Flexner
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence with Hans Freudenthal, K.O. Friedrichs, Paul Funk, and Harald Geppert
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence with the Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Göttingen, Georges Giraud, Victor M. Goldschimdt, Jakob Goldschmidt, Maria Goeppert-Meyer, Walter de Gruyter Verlag, Jacques Hadamard, Hans Hahn, Kurt Hahn
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with G. H. Hardy, Helmut Hasse, and Otto Haupt re: translation of mathematical works
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence with Einar Hille, Ernst Hellinger, Werner von Hentig, Gustav Herglotz, and Gustav Hertz
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Includes correspondence with David Hilbert, George de Hevesy, and Eberhard Hopf
    - Correspondence: Fakultät to Julia, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Includes correspondence with Heinz Hopf
    - Correspondence: Federal Reserve Bank, 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Includes correspondence with Fritz Courant and the Federal Reserve Bank re: money transfers to Fritz Courant in Brazil during World War II
    - Correspondence: Flexner, Abraham, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Material used by Constance Reid.
    - Correspondence: Flexner, Abraham, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Fragner, Adolf, 1938-1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Franck, James, 1931-1939, 1954-1956, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Franck, James, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Franck to M, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Material used by Constance Reid, includes correspondence with Louis J. Mordell, Erwin Madelung, Rudolf Lüneburg, Hans Lewy, Heinz Hopf, Kurt Hahn, and Hilda Geiringer
    - Correspondence: Friedrichs, K.O. (use copies), 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Friedrichs, K.O. (originals), 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Hasse, Helmut, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: H-K, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence with Otto Hahn, Paul Peter Ewald, Stefan Hildebrandt, and Heinz Hopf
    - Correspondence: Kamlah to Muntz, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence with Theodor von Karman, Oliver Kellogg, David Hilbert, and Hellmuth Kneser
    - Correspondence: Kamlah to Muntz, 1926-1933 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Correspondence with Rudolf Ladenburg, Edmund and Marianne Landau, son Mattias, Solomon Lefschetz, Derrick Henry Lehmer, Tuillio Levi-Civita, Hans Lewy, and Leon Lichtenstein
    - Correspondence: Kamlah to Muntz, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence with Konrad Knopp, Andrey Kolmogorov, Denes Konig (including rough draft of forward to Konig’s book Theorie der endlichen und unendlichen Graphen), Richard Konig, Gottfried Koethe, Nikolay Krylov, Robert Kuczynski, Erica Kueppers, and Justus Valentiner, Kurator of the University of Göttingen
    - Correspondence: Kamlah to Muntz, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence with Frederick Lindemann, Edward Hubert Linfoot, John Edensor Littlewood, Rudolf Lüneburg, Wilhelm Magnus, Kurt Mahler, and Heinz Maier-Leibniz, as well as a copy of the introduction to the English translation of Courant’s lectures on differential and integral calculus
    - Correspondence: Kamlah to Muntz, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with Hermann Francis Mark, Max Mason (President of the Rockefeller Foundation), Maria Goeppert-Mayer, and the Prussian Ministerium für Wissenschaft, Kunst, und Volksbildung (government agency responsible for German universities)
    - Correspondence: Kamlah to Muntz, 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence with Guste Minkowski (wife of Hermann Minkowski), Richard Mises, Louis J. Mordell, Marston Morse, C. Herman Müntz, as well as a letter from George Minot to David Hilbert re: treatments for Hilbert’s illness
    - Correspondence: Knesner, Hellmuth, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: L to Q, 1961-1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Includes correspondence with Saunders Mac Lane, Mikhail Lavrentyev, Gury Marchuk, Wilhelm Magnus, Frederick Seitz, Olga Oleinik, and William Prager
    - Correspondence: Mader to Zollamt, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Includes correspondence with Bartel van der Waerden, Hermann Weyl, Richard von Mises, Paul Oppenheim, Alexander Ostrowski, Justus Valentiner, Kurator of the University of Göttingen, Arnold Berliner (editor of Die Naturwissenschaften), the Prussian Ministerium für Wissenschaft, Kunst, und Volksbildung, and the Notgemeinschaft der Deutschen Wissenschaft (Emergency Association for German Science)
    - Correspondence: Mader to Zollamt, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Includes correspondence with Salvatore Pincherle, Robert Pohl, George Polya, Ludwig Prandtl, Georg Prange, Tibor Rado, Kurt Reidemeister, Albrecht Renner, Walther Rosemann, Arthur Rosenthal, Horst von Sanden (with Otto Blumenthal), Arnold Sommerfeld, Andreas Speiser, as well as correspondence with the Prussian Ministerium für Wissenschaft, Kunst, und Volksbildung re: construction of new Mathematical Institute using funds from the Rockefeller Institute, and materials relating to the death of Carl Runge (Courant’s father-in-law), including last will and testament
    - Correspondence: Mader to Zollamt, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Includes correspondence with Karl Scheel, Ludwig Schlesinger, Jan Arnoldus Schouten, Otto Schreier, Erwin Schrödinger, Elsa Schwarzschild (widow of Karl Schwarzschild), Edith Stein, Julius Stenzel, Wolfgang Sternberg, Carl and Hanna Still, Otto Toeplitz, and Justus Valentiner, Kurator of the University of Göttingen
    - Correspondence: Mader to Zollamt, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Includes correspondence with Alwin Walther, Andre Weil, William M. Whyburn, Eugene Wigner, Alexander Witting, as well as correspondence with the Prussian Ministry of Science, Art, and National Culture re: Courant's recommendations for professorial appointments at other German universities. Also includes a letter from E.L. Weatherburn to David Hilbert.
    - Correspondence: M to N (1 of 2), 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with Erwin Schrödinger, Anton E. Mayer, Ludwig von Mises, Thomas Hunt Morgan, Marston Morse, Chaim Muentz, and Otto Neugebauer
    - Correspondence: M to N (2 of 2), 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence with John von Neumann, Otto Neurath (re: International Institute for the Unity of Science), Jakob Nielsen, Gottfried Noether, Herman Nohl, and the Notgemeinschaft deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland (Emergency Society for German Scientists in Foreign Countries)
    - Correspondence: Nagumo to Reichsverband, 1929-1933 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with Arnold Berliner (as editor of Die Naturwissenschaften), Otto Neugebauer, John von Neumann, Rolf Nevanlinna, Max H. A. Newman, Jakob Nielsen, Charles Albert Noble, Emmy Noether, Bruno Jung (mayor of Göttingen), Alexander Ostrowski, Wolfgang Pauli, Nikolaus Pevsner, Mauro Picone, Robert Pohl, Hilda Geiringer (under married name Hilda Pollaczek), George Polya, William Prager, Ludwig Prandtl, Georg Prange, Alfred Pringsheim, Hans Rademacher, Tibor Rado, and Hans Reichenbach
    - Correspondence: Nagumo to Reichsverband, 1929-1933 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: "Nelli" [Nelly Neumann], 1915-1916 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence between Courant and Nelly Neumann post-divorce re: division of assets, legal documents pertaining to the divorce and legal bills from Courant’s lawyer.
    - Correspondence: N to Z, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Material used by Constance Reid. Includes correspondence with George Polya, William Prager, Kurt Reidemeister, Erich Rothe, Dolli Schoenberg, Wolfgang Sternberg, Carl and Hanna Still, Hermann Thiersch, Max Wertheimer, and Edmund T. Whittaker
    - Correspondence: Newman, M.H.A., 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Max H.A. Newman re: Courant’s one-year appointment at Cambridge in 1933-1934
    - Correspondence: O to R, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with Erwin Panofsky, Wolfgang Panofsky, Victor and Susanna Paschkis, Helene and Max Pick, Hilde Pick, Marcello Pirani, William Prager, Ludwig Prandtl, Hans Rademacher, and Tibor Rado
    - Correspondence: O to R, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence with Franz Rellich, Werner Richter, Herbert Robbins, Arthur Rosenthal, Erich Rothe, Iris Runge, and Wilhelm Runge
    - Correspondence: Re to Sel, 1929-1933 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence with Kurt Reidemeister (including a copy of the forward to his book on the foundations of geometry), R.G.D. Richardson, Howard Percy Robertson, Arthur Rosenthal, the rector of the Unviersity of Göttingen, as well as documents relating to Franz Rellich's Habilitation
    - Correspondence: Re to Sel, 1929-1933 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with Erich Rothe, mother-in-law Aimee Runge, sisters-in-law Aimee Luisa and Ella Runge, and brother-in-law Wilhelm Runge, Erich Salkowski, Horst von Sanden
    - Correspondence: R to Z, 1961-1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence with Constance Reid, Herbert Robbins, Wilhelm Runge, sister-in-law Iris Runge, Carl Siegel, Marianne Still (daughter-in-law of Carl Still), Lewis Strauss, F.K. Schmidt, Edward Teller, Hannah Vogt, Warren Weaver, Gian Carlo Wick, Margaret Wiener (wife of Norbert Wiener)
    - Correspondence: Rellich, Franz, 1947-1954, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Includes correspondence with Franz and Brigitte Rellich, Alwin Walther, and Erich Hecke
    - Correspondence: Sen to Sch, 1929-1933 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Separated Materials note
      Includes correspondence with Carl Siegel, Arnold Sommerfeld, Pauline Sperry, and Leo Spitzer
    - Correspondence: Sen to Sch, 1929-1933 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence with Otto Szasz, Gabor Szego, Julius Schrauder, Ludwig Schlesinger, F.K. Schmidt, Otto Schmidt, Abram Ioffe, Lev Schnirelman, Isaac Schoenberg, Jan Arnoldus Schouten, Erwin Schrödinger, Issai Schur, and Hans Schwerdtfeger
    - Correspondence: Shi to Stei, 1933-1937 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with Carl Siegel, David Eugene Smith, Frank Smithies, and Andreas Speiser
    - Correspondence: Shi to Stei, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with Hertha Sponer (and James Franck), Ferdinand Springer (and family), and Wolfgang Stechow
    - Correspondence: Sten to Struik, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence with Otto Stern, Wolfgang Sternberg, and Carl Still (and family)
    - Correspondence: Sten to Struik, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence with J.J. Stoker and Marshall Harvey Stone
    - Correspondence: Sullivan to Veblen, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence with Otto Szasz, Gabor Szego (including proposed outline of his 1939 book Orthogonal Polynomials), Jacob David Tamarkin, Olga Taussky-Todd, Hermann Thiersch, Stephen Timoshenko, and Otto Toeplitz
    - Correspondence: Sullivan to Veblen, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with Alan Turing, Helmut Ulm, and Oswald Veblen
    - Correspondence: S to Sp, 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence with Michael A. Sadowsky, George Sarton, and F.K. Schmidt
    - Correspondence: S to Sp, 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Includes correspondence with F.K. Schmidt
    - Correspondence: S to Sp, 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with with Iso and Dolly Schoenberg (daughter of Edmund Landau), Erwin Schrödinger, Heinz and Susanna von Schüching (daughter of Edmund Landau), Martin Schwarzschild, and Hans Schwerdtfeger
    - Correspondence: S to Sp, 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence with Else Staudinger, and Carl Siegel
    - Correspondence: Staiger to Zorn, 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with Wolfgang Sternberg, Carl and Hanna Still, Hans Stille, Simon Stoilow, Marshall Harvey Stone, Jacob David Tamarkin, Olga Taussky-Todd, Hermann Thiersch, Hans Thunsdorff, Stephen Timoshenko, Otto Toeplitz, and Leonida Tonelli
    - Correspondence: Staiger to Zorn, 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence with Erhard Tornier, Helmut Ulm, Oswald Veblen, Bartel van der Waerden, Alwin Walther, John Walz, Stefan Warschawski, and Werner Weber
    - Correspondence: Staiger to Zorn, 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with Andre Weil, Alexander Weinstein, Hermann Weyl, Norbert Wiener, Aurel Wintner, Edward Maitland Wright, Kunizo Yoneyama, Max Zacharias, Ernst Zermelo, and Max Zorn
    - Correspondence: St to Sz, 1936-1943 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with Hans Staehle, Martha Stein (Courant's cousin), Wolfgang Sternberg, Carl and Hanna Still, Marshall Harvey Stone, Lewis Strauss, Dirk Jan Struik, Otto Szasz, and Gabor Szego
    - Correspondence: Victoria to Zinnecker, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence with Tirukkannapuram Vijayaraghavan, Bartel van der Waerden, Alwin Walther, Warren Weaver, Alexander Weinstein, Max Wertheimer, Hermann Weyl, Anna Wheeler, and Edmund T. Whittaker
    - Correspondence: Victoria to Zinnecker, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence with Raymond L. Wilder, Rupert Wildt, Adolf Windaus, and Aurel Wintner
    - Correspondence: Weyl, Hermann, 1933-1934 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Whyte, John, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with John Whyte and Edward R. Murrow re: Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars as well as correspondence with Alfred Errera, Griffith C. Evans, Paul Peter and Ella Ewald, as well as Rose Ewald (P.P. Ewald's daughter)
    - Correspondence: John Wiley & Sons Inc. (Interscience Publishers), 1962-1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Correspondence re: Courant and Fritz John's textbook, Calculus.
    - Correspondence: Veblen, Oswald, 1933-1934 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Correspondence re: Courant's appointment at NYU.
  - Subseries B: Subject Files
    - Berlin Trading Company (Berliner Handelsgesellschaft), 1937-1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with the bank Berlin Handels-Gesellschaft. Includes information about the Courants' account there, before and after WWII.
    - Beyer, Herbert, 1952-1954 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with Werner Richter, Herbert Beyer re: restitution for firing and lost income at Göttingen after 1933.
    - Born, Max--Lectures (retirement), circa 1961 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Copies of lectures by Max Born, circa 1961, incl. “How I Became a Physicist.” “What I Did as a Physicist.” and “Reflections”
    - Bohr, Niels, 1950, 1967, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Copy of Niels Bohr's 1950 “Open Letter to the United Nations” about nuclear weapons control, excerpts (possibly galley prints) of pictures from a book/magazine article about the life of Niels Bohr. Also includes 1967 letter from Pavel Alexandroff to Nina Courant
    - Calculus I--Courant-John, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Calculus I--Royalties Agreement, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Differential and Integral Calculus, 1963, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Differential and Integral Calculus--Translation Bios, 1939, 1950-1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Differential and Integral Calculus--Portuguese Edition, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Differential and Integral Calculus--Publishers' Bios, 1937-1947 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Differential and Integral Calculus--Spanish Edition, 1940, 1950-1959 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Estate tax return, 1972 October (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Feld Telegraphie, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Materials relating to Courant’s service in the German Army in WWI, especially relating to earth telegraphy. An issue of the newspaper Die Rote Fahne has been removed to flat file storage.
    - Feld Telegraphie, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Materials (letters, telegrams, etc.) relating to Courant’s service in the German Army in WWI, including photographs of his telegraph apparatus
    - Feld Telegraphie, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      This folder contained several maps from WWI of the German front, trenches and testing areas for Courant's earth telegraph system as well as the certificate for the Military Merit Cross Courant received in 1916. The maps were relocated to flat storage and the certificate was moved to Box 96.
    - Feld Telegraphie, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Materials (letters, telegrams, etc.) relating to Courant’s service in German Army during WWI and his earth telegraphy system, including a typed description of how Courant’s machines worked
    - Foundations, Ford and Heineman, 1948-1949, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Göttingen Institute, 1926 undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Documents relating to 1926-1927 agreement between the University of Göttingen and the International Education Board of the Rockefeller Foundation on funding of new mathematical institute. Includes communication between Courant, Franck, and Augustus Trowbridge, the IEB’s head in Europe.
    - Göttingen--Correspondence re: Dismissal (1 of 2), 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Ferdinand Springer, publisher Hermann Weyl, Ludwig Prandtl, University Kurator Justus Valentiner, Max Reich, Hermann Thiersch, Helmut Hasse, as well as copies of relevant newspaper articles, original copy of the Nazi Civil Service Law, Courant’s official letter of forced retirement from 1935 and petition to the ministry to allow him to continue teaching.
    - Göttingen--Correspondence re: Dismissal (2 of 2), 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Introduction to Calculus and Analysis, 1965-1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Istanbul offer, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Legal Documents (copies), 1934-1935, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Contains copies of Courant’s marriage certificate, childrens' birth certificates. Also includes correspndence from early years at NYU.
    - [Methods of Mathematical Physics] Vol. III, Chap. 1 draft, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Italian edition, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Nazis, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Copies of Nazi documents from 1944-1945 requesting special permission to reprint Courant-Hilbert, Volume I.
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics--Publicity, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics I, II--Corrections, 1961-1966 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Methods of Mathematical Physics I, II--Translation Bios, 1949-1954, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Moscow, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Office of Alien Property claim forms, circa 1948 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Oppenheimer case (1 of 2), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Oppenheimer case (2 of 2), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Publication rights, 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Publication rights, 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Registration book (Göttingen), 1907-1910 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      Courant’s registration book from his years as a student in Göttingen, including list of courses, with instructors.
    - Religion--essays, papers (1 of 3), 1925, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
      Box 11, Folder 21-22 and Box 12, Folder 1 contain various essays about Christianity in Germany, sermons and church programs. Some of the essays were written by members of the Runge family.
    - Religion--essays, papers (2 of 3), 1902, 1916, 1933-1934, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Religion--essays, papers (3 of 3), 1927, 1940, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Foundation stipends, 1925-1927 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Includes letters between Courant (and Hilbert) and Rockefeller Foundation's IEB.